

Trista McCleary

CodeAndCoffeeLife.com linkedin.com/in/tristamccleary github.com/mccleary 404-376-2653 Atlanta, Ga trista_mccleary@yahoo.com

Summary

I am a strongly detail- oriented person with a love for organization and eager to apply those skills to web development. I am excited to continue to grow my web development skills and am looking for employers who make my continued learning a priority. Ideally, I'd like to work on a team of developers who enjoy their craft, are building interesting software, and who are open to mentoring and developing new talent. It's exciting to me that there is so much out there to learn, and I look forward to continuing to add to my skill set for many years to come.

Projects

FITLIFE

FitLife is a fitness eCommerce site designed to help those looking to get healthy, learn how to eat properly and lose weight. Meal plans are offered for both men and women. Look for workout plans coming soon! This project was made with the MEAN stack

Github: github.com/mccleary/fitlife

Demo: http://fitlifeforlife.us:5000/#/

AIRNAV

AirNav is an Atlanta Airport Navigation web application designed to help Atlanta airport travelers navigate through the world's busiest airport. This was a week long project built with a scrum team of four developers using agile development methodologies. Technologies used: HTML/CSS, Python, Angular, Leaflet, Sketch. *Our team won first place!

Github: https://github.com/DigitalCrafts-September-2016-Cohort/the_a_team2

Demo: https://airnavatl.com/#/home

GETCOHORT

GetCohort is a Coding Bootcamp built to showcase each student's projects and contact info as well as links to their email, portfolio, github and linkedIn sites. This was a week long project built with a scrum team of four developers using agile development methodologies. Technologies used: HTML/CSS, Python, Flask, PostgreSQL.*Our team tied for second place!

Github: https://github.com/DigitalCrafts-September-2016-Cohort/GetCohort

Demo: http://54.148.11.254/ (for testing - user: juan.cortes@gmail.com | pass: 1)

Experience

INSIDE SALES REP/PROCESSING SPECIALIST/INFRA-CHAMPION, INFRA-METALS - 2011-2015

- Responsible for account development and new business prospecting in a highly competitive market.
- Manage job quotations and tracking process while focusing on driving company's margin product line.
- Perform general sales functions -quotes, create job bids using T27 System based on duration of project length, data entry of sales, customer, quotes and invoices, apply industry knowledge, policies and procedures for questions and concerns posed while ensuring safety, scheduling of trucks with other departments to ensure commitment to the customer/client, Carbon Steel, Stainless, Aluminum

SOUTHEAST SENIOR BUYER, DIETRICH METAL FRAMING - 1998-2010

- Provided direction and leadership for more than 20 company buyers of manufacturing consumables; contained and reduced costs through successful price negotiations and vendor management, aided in efficient operation of purchasing policies and procedures, and ensured conformance to company purchasing objectives and policies.
- Consistently maintained supply chain flow, thus minimizing downtime and maximizing productivity. Software Trainer, Managed and trained buyers in Oracle, I-Procurement, Contempus, SOX compliance. Managed buyers for ten facilities in the Southeast and Midwest and purchased supplies for four facilities; provided back up purchasing for 25 additional locations.
- Achieved cost reduction of 10.5% (\$85K in six months) by identifying inventory efforts and managing reduction of manufacturing expenses through vendor consolidation, renegotiation of service contracts, freight reductions, and changing items being purchased.

Education

DigitalCrafts, Ga - **Certificate**, Full Stack Web Development (2017)

Clayton State University, Ga - AAS, Computer Networking (2006)

Clayton State University, Ga - Certificate, Computer Network Technician (2005)

Clayton State University, Ga - **BBA**, Business Management (2003)

Skills

- Web Development
- Software Training
- Purchasing Management
 Supply Chain Management
 Event Planning
 Project Management
 Vendor Management

- VMI/Consignment Inventory

- MRP/Inventory Control
- Production/Production Planning
- Sourcing
- Lean Manufacturing Concepts
- Customer Relations
 Staff Training/Team Building
 Multi-Level/Multi-location
- Continuous Improvement

Professional Organizations

PyLadiesATL - Member (Fall 2016 - present)

Women Who Code Atlanta - Member (Fall 2016 - present)